<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>William Spagnola</title>
    <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content on William Spagnola</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>William Spagnola</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wspagnola.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PATH Data and Sankey Diagrams</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/05/20/2021-05-20-exploring-states-of-tobacco-use-with-sankey-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/05/20/2021-05-20-exploring-states-of-tobacco-use-with-sankey-plots/</guid>
      <description>img { display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; }  Introduction While working toward my master’s degree in applied statistics, I interned at the Tobacco Research Lab at NYU’s College of Global Public Health. During my internship, I collaborated with another researcher to study changing smoking states over time. We were interested in answering questions such as what proportion of cigarette smokers quit and what proportion of former smokers relapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teacher Unions and NAEP Test Score Data</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/05/19/2021-05-17-unionization-and-naep-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/05/19/2021-05-17-unionization-and-naep-data/</guid>
      <description>Introduction As a former teacher, I’m often intrigued by the way in which education issues provoke such strong feelings among non-educators. Teacher unions tend to elicit particularly strong opinions.
Since so many people have strong opinions about unions, I decided to perform a state-level exploratory analysis of the relationship between test scores and unionization rates.
 Standard Correlation vs. Causation Caveat Of course, I need to start with the caveat that these data are purely correlational.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avoiding Flame Wars</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/04/20/2021-04-20-avoiding-flame-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/04/20/2021-04-20-avoiding-flame-wars/</guid>
      <description>Avoiding Flame Wars Before my life as a statistician/data analyst, I was a special education teacher in the Bronx with an undergraduate degree in English with a Spanish minor. At the time, I viewed the worlds of math and science as free from the subjective/emotional debates waged within the liberal arts. Little did I know, that turf wars seem to be endemic to all fields. During my graduate studies in statistics, I discovered that there were even intense disagreements about the fundamental nature of probability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a blog</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/04/17/2021-04-17-starting-a-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/2021/04/17/2021-04-17-starting-a-blog/</guid>
      <description>This is my first attempt at starting a statistics/data science blog. I hope to work on the following topics:
Potential List of Blog Topics  Statistics/Causal Inference through simulation My learning process as I explore new packages, programming functions Descriptions of the data analysis/machine learning projects in my Github Repo Interesting statistics papers as well as statistical topics trending on social media Tutorials of basic programming, statistical/machine learning concepts  My hope is that as I continue to write, I&amp;rsquo;ll get a better idea of which topics I would like to focus on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About Hello, my name is William (also Bill) Spagnola, and I&amp;rsquo;m passionate about exploring the intersection of data science and social science research. I enjoy using statistics/data analysis to solve real-world problems.
Organization I&amp;rsquo;m currently working for the Research Alliance for New York City Schools. My current projects include implementing a regression discontinuity design to identify the impact of Career Technical Education (CTE) on the graduation outcomes NYC high school students and developing a survey to evaluate the benefits of an after-school program designed to increase STEM awareness/engagement among disadvantaged students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Contact Info</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/page/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 02:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/page/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email wspagnola@nyu.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/page/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wspagnola.netlify.app/page/main/</guid>
      <description>Main Page Main page is under construction</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
